Aakriti Srivastava



- □ aakriti.sriv1912@gmail.com
- +918318652772
- Noida
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/aakritisrivastava-ab746213b

PROFILE

Professional Associate I Software Engineer with more than 4 years of experience in the field of Manual Testing. I am proud to share that I've got opportunities to work in Product based as well as Service based companies where I served some of the reputed clients. Experienced in with different PM working methodologies and software. Knowledge of financial and Health and Welfare Domain and I'm looking forward to being a part of a well-known organization that allows me to exhibit my technical skills and giving scope for career and financial growth.

AWARDS

Team Player- OTS Recognition -Conduent Business Service India LLP

Appreciating the efforts and commitment towards a successful Annual Enrollment project.

Honor role Individual (Quarter 1) -Conduent Business Service India LLP

Awarded for exemplary performance at the team level

SKILLS

SQL	••••
Jira	••••
Azure Devops	••••
Bug Reporting	••••
Test Planning	••••
Product Testing	••••
Functional Testing	••••
Smoke Testing	••••
Regression Testing	••••
Microsoft Excel	••••

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

S&P Global, Test Engineer

June 2022 – present | Noida

- Analyze the requirement coverage and traceability to ensure the testing coverage
- Test and Analysis of data as per trades e.g., PreTrade, PostTrade and Fixed Income
- Involved in database testing
- Involved in Manual Test, Regression testing, smoke testing and logged all the bug in tracking tool such as JIRA, Azure Devops, TFS etc
- Working closely with the software development team to ensure bug-free applications.
- Actively participating in all phases of product testing, including planning and delivery recommendations
- Providing guidance to interns and junior manual testers

Conduent Business Service India LLP, Test Engineer

October 2020 - May 2022 | Noida

- Successfully managed several critical projects and successfully achieved the project scheduled goals
- Responsible for reviewing business requirement.
- Analyze the requirement coverage and traceability to ensure the testing coverage
- Planned, supervised and coordinated daily activity of 1 junior business analysis engineer.
- Worked with team to understand the manual and provide feedback on the automable flows.

Shipgig Ventures Private Limited, Software Engineer

July 2019 – July 2020 | Noida

- Involved in designing test cases based on test Plan.
- Detecting the bugs and classifying them based on the severity and reporting.
- Involved in Functional Testing, G.U.I Testing and Cross browser Testing.
- Regression testing performed on every new build of the application.
- Reporting the Coverage status of test performed on the daily basis

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, Institute of Technology and management 2015 – 2019 | Gorakhpur

LANGUAGES

English Hindi



PROJECTS

Transaction cost analysis (TCA)

June 2022 - present

Description: Transaction cost analysis is a framework to analyze costs related to trading financial instruments compared to appropriate benchmarks. It allows financial professionals to quantify brokers' performance on trade execution, optimize trading algorithms, and improve their investment decision process

Responsibilities:

- Analyzed the business and functional requirement documents.
- Test and Analysis of data as per trades e.g., PreTrade, PostTrade and Fixed Income
- Involved in Manual testing, smoke testing, regression testing, sanity testing.
- Experience with good exposure towards testing techniques and methodologies and sound awareness of all the stages of Defect Life Cycle.
- Actively participating in all phases of product testing, including planning and delivery recommendations

US Healthcare Annual Enrollment (RiteAid Client)

October 2020 - May 2022

- Experience in Software testing and QA implementation for Client Server and web based application.
- Experience in pure Agile Systems
- Created report using SQL
- Worked on gathering requirement.
- Excellent understanding of Software development lie cycle and test methodologies.
- Expertise in black box testing, functional testing, integration testing, database testing and regression testing.
- Expertise in requirement analysis, writing test plan and test cases based on system requirement specification.
- Excellent hands on experience in handling the defect throughout the bug life cycle from detection until resolved using JIRA
- Expertise in designing and developing a strategic test plans, test cases, test scenarios, test reports
- Experienced in US health and welfare domain
- Strong ability in communicating decision choice options to the client.
- Participate in test meetings to discuss the testing progress and quality of the solution

HRMS

July 2019 - July 2020

- Working in Agile Testing Methodology.
- Test Cases creation and update, Test Cases execution, Defect Logging, review, tracking and retesting.
- Involved in System Integration Testing, Regression Testing, etc.